Rikesh Shah



rikeshshahshah@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/rikesh-shah-406903151



+91 98258 05034



https://rikeshshah.com/about

Summary

Hi, I am Rikesh Shah

I've been in the sales field for over 23 years, and have managed the state of Gujarat across various roles.

I am capable of training and appointing new sales officers. My network has allowed me to appoint various SE, SO, TSI, and even ASMs, and my experience has helped me train them in the ways of the company.

In budding companies, I have proved myself capable of building the sales infrastructure from the ground up. In stable companies, I have been able to manage and upgrade on the existing sales infra, including product launches and placements, as well as designing sales schemes, and countering competition's moves.

I have also been able to manage my relationships with my dealers and distributors, which has been helpful in better management of the product placement and marketing.

I can help your company at any stage of its sales growth, including:

- New area
- New customers
- New consumers
- New sales staff

Thank you.

Experience

Business Development Manager

Artline Group

May 2023 - Present (2 months)

Currently handling 2 A.S.M.s and 3 sales officers. Job also includes appointment of distributors and sales officers, designing beats and implementing coverage plans.

Also includes handling of 3 super-stockists throughout Gujarat, scheme implementation,

Branch Manager

Kores (India) Ltd.

Aug 2017 - Jun 2023 (5 years 11 months)

Handled all of Gujarat. Included 66 dealer and distributors across all districts, and managing 7 sales officers, and one ASM directly reporting to me.

Work also included designing product launch strategies and schemes, tracking competition activity and setting up countermeasures, and increasing area coverage.

Area Sales Manager

Dr. Reddy's Laboratories

Mar 2015 - Aug 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Handled sales operations of the state of Gujarat. Managed 9 sales officers, reporting directly to me. Designed sales routes. Handled product placement during launches and did other brand extensions as well.



Area Sales Manager

LT Foods LTD (D A A W A T Basmati Rice)

May 2014 - Mar 2015 (11 months)

Handled sales throughout Gujarat, i.e. Primary and Secondary Sales. Took care of 8 super stockists and 25 sub stockists. Managed 6 sales officers on company payroll, and paved way for sales infrastructure for new product launches in the state.



Makson Area Sales Manager

MAKSON GROUP

Nov 2013 - May 2014 (7 months)

Built sales infrastructure in the state of Gujarat from the start. Appointed new sales executives and representatives. Appointed super stockist and distributors.



Regional Growth Manager

Parle Agro Pvt Ltd

Aug 2012 - Nov 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Covering entire Central Gujarat, managing 19 growth officers on company payroll with direct reporting to me. Designed dispatch plans for distributors far from the depot. Focused on brand-wise achievements.



Area Sales Manager

Piramal Group

Jul 2009 - Jul 2012 (3 years 1 month)

Handled all OTC product sales for South Gujarat, covering 28 distributors across the territory, and handling 16 field force with directly answerable to me, delivering 60% growth year on year.



Territory Sales Incharge

Unilever

Jun 2004 - Jul 2009 (5 years 2 months)

Handled all FMCG Sales products of Hindustan Unilever, including food and beverages, and home and personal care.

Education



🎑 Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, Vadodara

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Chemistry

Apr 1994 - Apr 1997

Skills

General trade • Communication • Channel Sales • Marketing Management • Product Launch • Sales Schemes • Direct Sales • Product Placement • Sales Routes • Distributor Management